Hasanur Rahman Mohammad

Shakespeare Crescent, London, E12 6LN | 077538 198676 | <u>rahman.hm2002@gmail.com</u> | www.linkedin.com/in/hasanur-rahman-mohammad | github.com/Patatoni

Personal Profile

I am currently doing some remote internships in data science, and I am looking for more opportunities this summer to further develop my technical skills while also gaining experience working in a professional setting. Demonstrably excellent interpersonal skills by working for 3 years as a salesperson in a very high-pressure environment. I am very interested in the implementation of machine learning and deep learning models to solve real world problems, but more specifically how they can be used in robotics. I am a fast learner and am keen to take on new challenges to improve my skillset.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER | 2021-2024

BSc Computer Science

Activities and Societies: Course Representative, Badminton Club, Programming Society, Gaming Society

UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER | 2020-2021

Foundation year in Data Science and Analytics Activities and Societies: Course Representative.

NEWHAM SIXTH FORM | 2018-2020

UAL Level 3 Extended Diploma in Art and Design (Merit)

Activities: Badminton Club.

LANGDON ACADEMY | 2013-2018

10 GCSEs including Mathematics (6) and English (7).

Experience

DATA SCIENCE INTERN | GLOBALCERT | MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- Working on real world problems and using data analysis and visualization to solve them.
- Using popular python libraries for data visualization and manipulation such as NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib and scikit-learn.
- Learn to build real world machine learning models to solve problems.
- Understanding how to generate business insights and proposals to present to stakeholders.

DATA SCIENCE INTERN | GRIP THE SPARKS FOUNDATION | MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- Working independently on several tasks assigned by the mentors. Sample data was given, and I was asked to create a prediction model to find a solution to given case study.
- Currently learning more about python libraries to work with the data given such as NumPy and Pandas among others.

SALES ASSOCIATE | H. SAMUEL | NOVEMBER 2018–2021

- Engaged with a variety of new and regular customers daily in a warm and friendly manner, whilst always providing outstanding customer service.
- Handling customer complaints in a calm and collected manner while under pressure during busy periods.
- Working as part of a team to achieve and often exceed the stores sales target for the period by as much as 15%, allowing us to be on track to make £1 million in sales for the year, £250k per period.
- Maintaining a company set standard of 20% warranty strike rate throughout each sales period.
- Responsible for maintaining a high-quality standard for the watches display section in the shop.
 - O Dealing with watch deliveries and putting the watches in their designated places whether they go out or are reserves.
 - Routinely cleaning and organizing the watch displays to make sure all our products are ready to be bought by customers.

TECHNOLOGY INTERN | BRIGHT NETWEORK | JUNE 2021

- Attended online talks about the inner workings of a tech company and how a software engineer fits into it all. Talks were led by industry professionals from leading companies Google, Accenture, Vodafone, EY, and Amazon.
- Completed python workshops given by Google, after which I did a simple coding challenge to test the knowledge gained.
- While working in a group I did a Microsoft PowerPoint about technology consulting given by EY.

Core Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java

SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Teamwork, Adaptability, Independent worker, Problem solving, Creativity.

LANGUAGES

English, Italian, Spanish, Bengali.